A Collection of Scrapbooks LSC.0155
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Scrapbook no. 18 vol. 10: McClurkin, James Robert, 1910 -. Scrapbooks re: World War II, 1941 - 1945; 13 volumes (Box 85)
  Volumes 10 - 13 are titled: "We were there," and consist of a journal volume (typescript and holograph), 2 vols. of correspondence mostly from JRMC to his wife and 1 vol. of clippings and personal memorabilia. Gift of JRMC, Sept. 1947 and Feb. 1974
- Scrapbook no. 180: Post card album, Ca. 1910s; 1 vol. (Box 145)
  Includes views of Great Britain, France, Switzerland and Canada
- Scrapbook no. 181: Cooper, Alfred W. 300 pencil drawings and 17 watercolors, 1859 - 1866; 2 vols. (Box 145)
  Cooper is listed in British ms. catalog as an illustrator. [Vol 2 not found 11/91]
- Scrapbook no. 182: YMCA clippings, New York, 1899 - 1910; 1 vol. (Box 145)
- Scrapbook no. 183: King Tut clippings from the Illustrated London News and Illustrated London News Coronation Number, 1923 - 1929, 1937; 1 vol. (Box 146)
- Scrapbook no. 184: Theater scrapbook, New York, Ca 1910s; 1 vol. (Box 147)
- Scrapbook no. 185: B.F. Keitlis's Theater, Providence, RI, cast lists, 1915 - 1916; 1 vol. (Box 147)
- Scrapbook no. 186: Theater cast lists and scenes from some plays, Ca. 1900s; 1 vol. (Box 148)
- Scrapbook no. 187: Theater programs, London, 1880s - 1890s; 1 vol. (Box 148)
- Scrapbook no. 188: Victorian scrapbook, Ca. 1880s; 1 vol. (Box 149)
  Chromolithographed punch scrap depicting children, animals and other things
- Scrapbook no. 189: Oxley, E.B. Greeting cards and chromolithographed punch scrap of flowers, animals and birds, 1883 - 1884; 1 vol. (Box 149)
- Scrapbook no. 190: Victorian scrapbook of chromolithographed punch scrap depicting religious scenes, Ca. 1880s; 1 vol. (Box 150)
- Scrapbook no. 191: British clippings about the Bacon/Shakespeare question, 1888; 1 vol. (Box 150)
- Scrapbook no. 192: Theater scrapbook, New York, 1920 - 1925; 1 vol. (Box 151)
- Scrapbook no. 193: Original water colors and clipped British cartoons, Ca. 1880s; 1 vol. (Box 151)
- Scrapbook no. 194: McCutcheon, George Barr, "Graustark: the story of love behind the throne", 1901; 1 vol. (Box 151)
  Reviews, etc.
- Scrapbook no. 195: American miscellany from the mid-1930s including post cards, clippings of stars and art, Ca. 1934 - 1938; 1 vol. (Box 152)
- Scrapbook no. 196: Clippings from Southern California newspapers on local news items, 1900 - 1912; 1 vol. (Box 152)
- Scrapbook no. 197: Pasha, Emin, explorer of Africa. Reprinted photographs, Ca. 1840 - 1880; 1 vol. (Box 153)
- Scrapbook no. 198: Association of Bank Women / Women Bankers, 1921 - 1940; 1 vol. (Box 153)
- Scrapbook no. 199: Detroit theater programs and broadsides, 1878 - 1886; 1 vol. (Box 154)
- Scrapbook no. 200: Greenwich Village Theater, 1916 - 1920; 1 vol. (Box 155)
- Scrapbook no. 201: New York theater, 1908 - 1912; 1 vol. (Box 155)
- Scrapbook no. 202: "Literature and general information", 1904 - 1905; 1 vol. (Box 156)
  Newsclippings. Gift of Albert Boni, ex-libris T.K. Peters
- Scrapbook no. 203: Los Angeles theater programs, Ca. 1938 - 1945; 1 vol. (Box 156)
- Scrapbook no. 204: Theater programs: London and New York, 1900 - 1910; 1 vol. (Box 157)
- Scrapbook no. 205: Engraved labels from wine bottles, trade cards, etc., Ca. 1830 - 1890; (approx.) 500 items (Box 157)
- Scrapbook no. 206: Book plates and tickets, 1760 - 1900; 1 vol. (Box 158)
- Scrapbook no. 207: Clippings about Shakespeare, 1860 - 1870; 1 vol. (Box 158)
- Scrapbook no. 208: Lithographs and original sketches of Europe, Ca. 1880s; 1 vol. (Box 159)
- Scrapbook no. 209: Poems and sketches, 1847; 1 vol. (Box 159)
- Scrapbook no. 210: Autograph book, 1876; 1 vol. (Box 159)
- Scrapbook no. 211: "Book notices, Newton Booth Mines", Ca. 1860 - 1890; 1 vol. (Box 159)
- Scrapbook no. 212: Autographs and letters, Ca. 1860 - 1880; 1 vol. (Box 159)
- Scrapbook no. 213: Illustrations "from old books", Ca. 1800s; 1 vol. (Box 160)
- Scrapbook no. 214: Clippings of poems and illustrations, Ca. 1870 - 1880; 1 vol. (Box 160)
- Scrapbook no. 215: Poems, original watercolors and clipped illustrations, Ca. 1820 - 1880; 1 vol. (Box 160)
- Scrapbook no. 216: Notes, sketches and clipped illustrations, Ca. 1820 - 1880; 1 vol. (Box 160)
- Scrapbook no. 217: "Possible history of Eleanor van Worthington age 3 months, Jan. 16, 1912, Geneva Illinois", 1 vol. (Box 160)
  Magazine illustrations with handwritten captions telling a story
- Scrapbook no. 218: British photographs, autographs and clippings, Ca. 1890s; 2 vols. (Box 161)
- Scrapbook no. 219: Victorian chromolithographed punch scrap, Ca. 1880s; 1 vol. (Box 162)
- Scrapbook no. 220: Artwork made from little tiny commemorative seals, 19th c.; 1 vol. (Box 162)
- Scrapbook no. 221: English Lake District: local interest clippings, Ca. 1895 - 1902; 1 vol. (Box 162)
- Scrapbook no. 222: Victorian chromolithographed punch scrap, Ca. 1880s; 1 vol. (Box 162)
- Scrapbook no. 223: Sketch book, 19th c.; 1 vol. (Box 162)
- Scrapbook no. 224: Postcard album, USA, 1 vol. (Box 163)
- Scrapbook no. 225: Victorian chromolithographed punch scrap depicting flowers and animals, Ca. 1880s; 1 vol. (Box 163)
- Scrapbook no. 226: Victorian chromolithographed punch scrap depicting flowers and animals, Ca. 1880s; 1 vol. (Box 163)
- Scrapbook no. 227: Italian and German trade cards, 1869; 200 items (Box 163)
- Scrapbook no. 228: Playbills, USA, Ca. 1880 - 1895; 1 vol. (Box 164)
- Scrapbook no. 229: Playbills, USA, Ca. 1870 - 1885; 1 vol. (Box 164)
- Scrapbook no. 230: "Theater record and scrapbook", Ca. 1899 - 1900; 1 vol. (Box 164)
  Contains playbills, tickets and clippings, USA
- Scrapbook no. 231: Playbills, USA, Ca. 1870s; 1 vol. (Box 164)
- Scrapbook no. 232: "Theater programs, season 1912 - 1913", 1 vol. (Box 165)
  Clippings, USA
- Scrapbook no. 233: Playbills and theater clippings glued over a ledger, USA, 1890s; 1 vol. (Box 166)
- Scrapbook no. 234: Playbills, Germany and USA, 1890s; 1 vol. (Box 166)
- Scrapbook no. 235: Playbills, Germany and USA, 1880s - 1890s; 1 vol. (Box 166)
- Scrapbook no. 236, vol. 1: Theater programs and clippings, 1918 - 1945; 3 vols. (Box 167)
  USA.
- Scrapbook no. 236, vol. 2: Theater programs and clippings, 1940 - 1941; 3 vols. (Box 167)
- Scrapbook no. 236, vol. 3: Theater programs and clippings, 1910 - 1948; 3 vols. (Box 167)
- Scrapbook no. 237: "Chloe's Journey", 1930; 1 vol. (Box 168)
  Scrapbook of Chloe's trip to Europe. She was born in 1877 and the scrapbook includes her passport
- Scrapbook no. 238: Clippings regarding problems between labor and management, chiefly in San Francisco shipyards, 1919 - 1926; 1 vol. (Box 168)
- Scrapbook no. 239: Knox, Agnes, 1867 - 1891; 1 vol. (Box 169)
  Collection of seals, shields and symbols, presumably from the cards and letterheads of her various correspondents. Formerly#r 155/57.
- Scrapbook no. 240: Scrapbook of an unidentified (British?) woman, 19th century; 1 vol. (Box 169)
  Contains sketches, watercolors, pressed flowers, chromolithographed punchscrap and clippings. Formerly #155/57.
- Scrapbook no. 241: Romantic scrapbook, ca. 1840s; 1 vol. (Box 169)
  Poems and botanically exact illustrations presumably written and drawn by a woman named Margaret in england. Many of the illustrations are of exotic flowers. Incl. the stirring query, "Pourquois est l'amour comme le pomme de terre."
- Scrapbook no. 242: Theater scrapbook, 1941 Nov - 1944 Jun; 1 vol. (Box 170)
  Programs and clippings on Los Angeles productions.
- Scrapbook no. 243: Theater scrapbook, 19th century; 1 vol (Box 170)
  Clippings of actors and actresses, probably from New York theaters.
- Scrapbook no. 244: Theater scrapbook, 1890 - 1900; 1 vol. (Box 170)
  Clippings and programs from New York and other cities.
- Scrapbook no. 245: Irving, Paul, 1910s; 1 vol. (Box 170)
  Photographs, programs and clippings relating to productions in which Irving was involved.
- Scrapbook no. 246: Theater scrapbook, ca. 1905 - 1936; 1 vol. (Box 170)
  Programs and clippings regarding various productions and players in various U.S. cities.
- Scrapbook no. 247: Sounders, Robert R, 1944-1946; 1 vol. (Box 170)
  Programs and clippings from various Los Angeles theatrical productions attended by Sounders.
- Scrapbook no. 248: Theater scrapbook, 1900-1905; 1 vol. (Box 171)
  British theater programs.
- Scrapbook no. 249: Theater scrapbook, 1907 - 1910; 2 vols. (Box 171)
  Clippings of actors and actresses.
- Scrapbook no. 250: California theatrical programs, 1894 - 1896; 1 vol. (Box 172)
- Scrapbook no. 251: Theater scrapbook, ca. 1890 - 1920; 1 vol. (Box 172)
  New York.
- Scrapbook no. 252: Theater scrapbook, 1891 - 1893; 1 vol. (Box 172)
  Clippings from various U.S. cities.
- Scrapbook no. 253: Theater scrapbook, 1893 - 1909; 1 vol. (Box 172)
  Clippings and programs, mainly from New York.
- Scrapbook no. 254: Theater programs and clippings, 1913 - 1915; 2 vols. (Box 172)
- Scrapbook no. 255: War diary of World War for 1918 - 1919, 1 vol. (Box 173)
  World War I scrapbook kept by Catherine Johnson, aged 10-11, of Montclair, New Jersey.
- Scrapbook no. 256: World War II newspaper maps, 1935 - 1960; 1 vol. (Box 174)
  Collection of maps from Chicago area newspapers from 1935-1960. Most are color maps of World War II battlegrounds and campaigns. A few maps at the end of the scrapbook cover the Korean War and the war in French Indo-China. 61 x 51 cm.
- Scrapbook no. 257: Hollywood High School scrapbook, 1955; 1 vol. (Box 175)
- Scrapbook no. 258: Zemaitija, Lithuania scrapbooks, 1935-1946; 2 vols. (Box 176)
  2 scrapbooks of clippings mostly about Zemaitija. Volume 2 contains a long article on Henry Morton Stanley. 23.5 x 20 cm.
- Scrapbook no. 259: Silverwood's Department Stores, Los Angeles, ca. 1924-1931; 1 vol. (Box 177)
  Correspondence and clippings. Purchase, Dawson's, 1988.
- Scrapbook no. 260: Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation, ca. 1980-1983; 4 vols. (Box 178)
  Volumes 1-4. Clippings and tear outs.
- Scrapbook no. 260: Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation, ca. 1970-1981; 3 vols. (Box 179)
  Volumes 5-7. Clippings and tear outs.
- Scrapbook no. 261: Harlow, Jean, no date; 1 vol. (Box 179)
- Scrapbook no. 262: Cleopatra (Motion picture), 1959; 1 vol. (Box 179)
  Featuring Elizabeth Taylor.
- Scrapbook no. 263: Glass Menagerie, 1960; 1 vol. (Box 180)
  German press clippings.
- Scrapbook no. 264: Sebert, Jean, ca. 1960s; 4 vols. (Box 180)
  Clippings and photographs.
- Scrapbook no. 265: Schell, Maria, ca. 1960s; 2 vols. (Box 180)
- Scrapbook no. 266: Dynasty (Television program), 1981-1986; 4 vols. (Box 181)
  Photocopies of clippings, seasons 1-6.
- Scrapbook no. 267: Movie Star picture cards, ca.1920s-1950s; 1 vol. (Box 182)
- Scrapbook no. 268: Ford, Wallace, ca. 1930s; 2 vols. (Box 183)
  Volumes 1-2.
- Scrapbook no. 268: Ford, Wallace, ca. 1930s; 3 vols. (Box 184)
  Volumes 3-5.
- Scrapbook no. 269: Louisa (Motion picture), 1950-1953; 1 vol. (Box 185)
  Film from Universal International.
- Scrapbook no. 270: Lets Make Love (Motion Picture), 1959-1960; 1 vol. (Box 186)
  Film from Twentieth Century Fox. Press clippings from Great Britain.
- Scrapbook no. 271: Dix, Richard, 1923, 1925; 2 vols. (Box 187)
- Scrapbook no. 272: Holt, Jack, 1922-1923; 2 vols. (Box 188)
- Scrapbook no. 273: Griffith, Corrine, 1926-1927; 1 vol. (Box 189)
- Scrapbook no. 274: Barrymore, Lionel, 1923-1924; 1 vol. (Box 189)
- Scrapbook no. 275: Peck, Gregory, 1960s; 1 vol. (Box 190)
- Scrapbook no. 276: Lowe, Edmund, 1924-1925; 1 vol. (Box 190)
- Scrapbook no. 277: Gigot (Motion picture), 1961; 1 vol (Box 191)
  Mostly copies of French clippings on thermofax paper.
- Scrapbook no. 278: Julia Cornell scrapbook & letters, 1930 - 1931; 1 vol. (Box 192)
  Argentina & the September Revolution,
- Scrapbook no. 279: Death Valley, ca.1927; 1 vol. (Box 193)
  Motion picture; Writer: Raymond Wells, Director: Paul Powell.
- Scrapbook no. 280: Of Mice and Men, 1939 March; 2 vols. (Box 194)
  Play at the El Capitan theater; featuring Wallace Ford.
- Scrapbook no. 281: One Foot in Hell, 1960; 1 vol. (Box 194)
  Press clippings from Great Britain.
- Scrapbook no. 282: Warner Baxter, 1943 - 1951; 1 vol. (Box 194)
  Press clippings.
- Scrapbook no. 283: I Met Him in Paris, 1937; 1 vol. (Box 194)
  Publicity Department Rio de Janeiro Brazil (in Portuguese).
- Scrapbook no. 284: Teet Carle, 1930s; 1 vol. (Box 194)
  Articles by Teet Carl.